Finding Aid for Mary Stewart Papers, 1980-2015
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Mary Stewart papers
1980-2015
Stewart, Mary.
0.4 linear feet
79.9 GB online
2015043 Aa 2
Mary Stewart served as an events coordinator at the University of Michigan Union from 1974-2015. Stewart's role evolved into a sympathetic mentor and resource for minority students and student athletes within the University. The records consists of photographs, correspondence, and news articles relating to Stewart's time at the University.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by Mary Stewart (donor no. 11293 ), in July, 2015.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
Mary Stewart served as an events coordinator at the University of Michigan Union. Stewart jointed the Union in 1974. In the 1980s, Stewart noticed there were few events at the Union for black students. Stewart began working with Omega Psi Phi fraternity to find sponsors and help fund and organize events. Stewart's work with Omega Psi Phi led to other organizations to ask for help. Stewart assumed an unofficial role as sympathetic mentor, counselor, and resource for minority students and student athletes within the university. Among Stewart's mentees were Larry Foote, Derek Jeter, Morgan Trent, Mike Hart, Chris Perry, and many others.
Stewart retired from the University of Michigan in 2015. A group of Stewart's mentees, led by Mike Muse (Obama administration adviser and CEO of Muse records) and Glenn Eden (Chicago based public relations executive) has established a scholarship in Stewart's name in conjunction with the U-M Alumni Association's LEAD Scholars Program. The first scholarship was awarded at a testimonial celebration for Stewart on October 9, 2015.
The records are arranged into three series: Correspondence, Photographs, and Digital Materials.
The Mary Stewart Papers consists of photographs, correspondence, and news articles relating to Stewart's time at the University of Michigan Union.
Subjects:
Athletics--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Greek letter societies--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Hart, Mike.; Jeter, Derek, 1974-; Minority college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Stewart, Mary.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.StudentsSocieties, etc.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Athletes--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Genre Terms:
Digital file formats.; Photographs.
- Correspondence, 1980-2013 (Box 1)
  The Correspondence series (1980-2013, 0.2 linear feet) consists of letters, notes, and invitations sent to Stewart.
  - 1980-2013 (Box 1)
- Photographs, 1992-2014
  The Photographs series (1992-2014 and undated, 0.2 linear feet) contains pictures of students, organizations, and athletes that Stewart mentored. The photos were mounted in a collage in Stewart's office and came to be known as "Mary Stewart's Wall" or simply "The Wall."
  - Calvin Bell, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - Larry Foote, undated (Box 1)
  - Mike Hart, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Derek Jeter, 1992-2014 (Box 1)
  - Marshall Lyons, undated (Box 1)
  - Ryan Mundy, undated (Box 1)
  - Mike Muse, undated (Box 1)
  - Chris Perry, undated (Box 1)
  - Morgan Trent, 2010-2012 (Box 1)
  - Alpha Phi Alpha, undated (Box 1)
  - Black Vibes, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Delta Sigma Theta, undated (Box 1)
  - Kappa Alpha Psi, 2000-2004 (Box 1)
  - Phi Beta Sigma, undated (Box 1)
  - Omega Psi Phi, 1996-2009 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Gamma Rho, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Students and Staff, 2000-2012 (Box 1)
  - Unlabeled, 1994-2014 (Box 1)
- Digital Materials
  The Digital Materials series (2015, 79.9 GB) contains a "Thank You" video and news articles relating to Stewart's retirement.
  - "Thank You" Video, 2015; ZIP File
    (To honor Mary Stewart's service as a mentor and confidant to hundreds of University of Michigan students, some of her favorite Michigan Men created a video to say thank you)
  - News Articles, 2015; ZIP File
    (Includes pdf files and .warc files (an internet archive format) of the same items)